

🛙 (+1) 415-867-7062 | 🗷 thanpetsas@gmail.com | 😭 www.thanasispetsas.com | 🛅 thanasis-petsas | 🞓 Thanasis Petsas

Summary _____

R&D Engineer primarily focused on Mobile Security and Privacy. With 6+ years experience in Mobile Security mainly on Android platform, focusing on areas spanning app analysis, malware evasion, mobile user tracking, as well as the design and implementation of defense schemes and systems able to protect user's privacy on these environments. Always interested in working on new challenging tasks and devising new techniques and methods to tackle problems, as well as passionate about learning new technologies and tools.

Skills_

Programming C/C++ · Python · Java · Bash · SQL

Tools IDA Pro · Android JNI/NDK · Android ADB · Mitmproxy **DevOps** AWS · GCP · Terraform · Jenkins · CircleCl · Airbrake · Git

Experience ____

Symantec (A division of Broadcom Software)

San Francisco, CA

Oct. 2018 - Now

R&D ENGINEER

· Developed a framework for faking Android and iOS sensors for enhancing our dynamic analysis engines

- Updated our dynamic analysis hooking engines to be compatible with Android (9.0) Pie
- Transitioned with SEP (Symantec Endpoint Protection) Mobile team into Broadcom
- Implemented a malicious hotspot detection feature on iOS SEP Mobile app
- Developed unit tests for increasing code coverage of iOS SEP Mobile app

Appthority San Francisco, CA

R&D ENGINEER Oct 2015 - Oct. 2018

- Implemented dynamic features for detecting specific behaviors of Android applications
- Updated our dynamic analysis hooking engines to be compatible with Android (8.0) Oreo

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

San Francisco, CA

· Developed smart techniques for exercising multiple execution paths during dynamic analysis of Android apps

Heraklion, Crete, Greece

Oct. 2015 - Dec. 2015

Nov. 2012 - Sep. 2015

POSTGRADUATE FELLOW

ICS - FORTH

- Study on modeling of app popularity in Android application marketplaces
- Implementation of emulation evasion techniques on Android
- Energy consumption analysis of Android Anti-Virus software
- · Implementation of an anti-tracking mechanism for Android that preserves users privacy during browsing

Honors & Awards

Best Paper Honorable Mention, 26th International World Wide Web Conference (WWW '17)

Perth, Australia Fukuoka, Japan

2012 Gold Prize, Malware-analysis competition "IWSEC Cup 2012" (IWSEC '12)

Education

University of Crete

M.Sc. in Computer Science – GPA: $9.0\,\mathrm{out}$ of $10.0\,\mathrm{out}$

Heraklion, Crete, Greece Oct. 2009 - Nov. 2012

University of Crete

Heraklion, Crete, Greece

B.Sc. in Computer Science – GPA: $7.56\,\mathrm{out}$ of $10.0\,\mathrm{in}$

Sept. 2004 - Jul. 2009

Selected Publications

- Elias Papadopoulos, Michalis Diamantaris, Panagiotis Papadopoulos, Thanasis Petsas, Sotiris Ioannidis, and Evangelos Markatos. The Long-Standing Privacy Debate: Mobile Websites Vs Mobile Apps. In WWW '17, Perth, Western Australia, 2017. (Best Paper Honorable Mention).
- · Iasonas Polakis, Michalis Diamantaris, Thanasis Petsas, Federico Maggi, and Sotiris Ioannidis. Powerslave: Analyzing the Energy Consumption of Mobile Antivirus Software. In DIMVA '15, Milano, Italy, 2015.
- Thanasis Petsas, Giannis Voyatzis, Elias Athanasopoulos, Michalis Polychronakis, and Sotiris Ioannidis. Rage Against the Virtual Machine: Hindering Dynamic Analysis of Android Malware. In EuroSec '14, Amsterdam, The Netherlands, 2014.
- Thanasis Petsas, Antonis Papadogiannakis, Michalis Polychronakis, Evangelos P. Markatos, and Thomas Karagiannis. Rise of the Planet of the Apps: A Systematic Study of the Mobile App Ecosystem. In IMC '13, Barcelona, Spain, 2013.

THANASIS PETSAS · RÉSUMÉ FEBRUARY 25, 2022